Blair and Lee Family Papers, 1640-1946 (bulk 1812-1920 ): Finding Aid C0614
Manuscripts Division
- Papers of Samuel Phillips Lee, 1772-1897; 1812-1897; 178 boxes
  - Logs, Journals, Notebooks, and Registers, 1827-1898 May 28; 12 boxes
    Consists of the logs, journals, notebooks, and registers of Samuel Phillips Lee, primarily pertaining to naval subjects and the Silver Springs Farm.
    - Naval, 1827-1888; 7 boxes
      Contains logbooks and journals for ships, including the Washington, Legare, Vincennes, Brandywine, Oneida, as well as notebooks on naval surveys and exploration, and registers of bills, signals, requisitions, surveys vessels boarded, and orders.
      - Logs and Journals, 1835-1866; 3 boxes
        - U.S.S. Nautilus, 1846; U.S. Brig Washington, 1847; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - U.S. Brig Washington, 1847 May-July; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 2)
        - U.S. Brig Washington, 1847 August-November; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 3)
        - U.S. Brig Washington, 1848; U.S. Steamer Legare, 1849; U.S. Steamer Vixen, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 4)
        - U.S. Steamer Legare, 1849-1850; U.S. Steamer Walker, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 5)
        - U.S. Steamer Legare, 1850; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 6)
        - U.S.S. Vincennes, 1835; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - U.S. Frigate Brandywine, 1834-1835; U.S. Ship Vincennes, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 2)
        - Wilkes Exploring Expedition (U.S.S. Peacock), 1838-1839; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 3)
        - U.S.S. Oneida, 1862; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 4)
        - U.S. Practice Ship "Marion", 1863; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 5)
        - U.S. Flagship "Malvern", 1864; 1866; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 6)
        - Journal / Log, 1863-1864; 1 box (Box 56)
      - Notebooks, 1827-1888; 2 boxes
        - Navigation notebooks, 1842-1864; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 1)
          3 notebooks.
        - Notebooks and notes on naval surveys and exploration, 1838-1854; 3 folders (Box 57, Folder 2-4)
        - Miscellaneous notebooks, 1860-1888; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 5)
        - Notebooks and notes on naval subjects, 1827-1856; 2 folders (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
        - Navigation notebook, 1842-1864; 2 folders (Box 58, Folder 3-4)
      - Registers, 1869-1872; 2 boxes (Box 59, Box 60)
    - Silver Spring Farm Logs, 1868-1898 May 28; 4 boxes
      Contains daily accounts of farm projects accomplished, equipment and supplies needed or laid in, new long-term plans as well as short-term goals, the status of crops, etc.
      - Logs, 1873 March 20 - 1874 January 12; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Logs, 1874 August 21 - 1875 January 4; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Logs, 1875; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Logs, 1875 - 1878 July 19; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Logs, 1875 December 9 - 1878 July 8; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Logs, 1878 August 1 - 1880 May 31; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Logs, 1868; 1878 December 9 - 1881 March 25; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Logs, 1880 June 1 - 1881 September 30; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Logs, 1881 October 1 - 1883 April 30; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Logs, 1883 May 1 - 1884 March 1; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Logs, 1884 January 12 - 1885 June 10; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Logs, 1884 March 1 - 1885 July 31; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Logs, 1885 August 1 - 1887 March 12; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Logs, 1885 August 9 - 1888 April 30; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Logs, 1887 March 17 - 1887 September 27; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Logs, 1888 May 1 - 1891 September 30; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Logs, 1891 October 1 - 1894 May 31; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Logs, 1894 June 1 - 1897 April 30; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Logs, 1897 May 1 - 1897 June 3; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Logs, 1897 July 13 - 1898 May 28; 1 folder (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1851-1862; 1 box (Box 65)
  - Correspondence, 1772-1912; 77 boxes
    Consists of the correspondence of Samuel Phillips Lee, including letterbooks from his time in the Navy, family correspondence, naval correspondence, real estate correspondence, and general correspondence.
    Arranged by genre of correspondence.
    - Letterbooks, 1847 March-1897; 7 boxes
      Contains copies of letters written while Lee was an officer in the navy, as well as letters written to naval personnel after his retirement in 1873, and copies of personal and business letters, particularly those dealing with real estate.
      - Naval, 1847 March-1872; 4 boxes
        - Naval, 1847 March-1848 April; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 1)
        - Naval, 1848 April-November; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 2)
        - Naval, 1848 December 16 - 1849 July 25; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 3)
        - Naval, 1849 July-1850 January; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 4)
        - Naval, 1850 January-December; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 5)
        - Naval, 1850 December-1852 July; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 6)
        - Naval, 1852-1869; 1 box (Box 67)
        - Naval, 1870-1872; 1 box (Box 68)
        - North Atlantic Blocking Squadron; 1864-1865, Mississippi Squadron, 1862-1863; 1 box (Box 69)
      - Personal, Real Estate, and Naval: Letterbooks, 1863-1897; 3 boxes (Box 70, Box 71, Box 72)
    - Family, 1784-1897; 13 boxes
      Contains letters received while Lee was an officer in the navy, as well as letters written to naval personnel after his retirement in 1873, and copies of personal and business letters, particularly those dealing with real estate.
      - Elizabeth Blair Lee, 1839-1894; 8 boxes
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1839; 1842; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1843; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1844; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1846 May -August 15; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1846 August 17-November 22; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1847 March -July 13; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1847 July 22-November 12; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1848 May-August; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1848 September-November; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1849; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1850; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1851 January -September 13; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1851 September 15 - December; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1851-1852; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1854; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 8)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1855; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1856; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1857; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1858; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1859; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1860; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1861 January-August; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1861 September-December; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 8)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1862 January -April 8; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1852 April 10 - June; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1862 July-September; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1862 October-December; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 January-February; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 March-April; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 May-June; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 July-August; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 September-October; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1863 November-December; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864 January -February 19; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864 February 20 - April; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864 May-June; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864 July-August; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864 September-October; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864 November-December; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1865 January; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1865 February; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1865 March-May; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1865 June-August; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1866; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 8)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1867; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 9)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1868; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 10)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1869; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1870; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1871 January-February; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1871 March-April; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1871 May; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1871 June; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1871 July-September; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1872 January-February; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1872 March-April; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 2)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1872 May-June; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 3)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1872 July-November; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1875-1878; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 5)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1879; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1880; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 7)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1882-1883; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 8)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1884-1885; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 9)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1887; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 10)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1891-1894; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 11)
        - Elizabeth Blair Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, undated; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - John F. Lee, 1837-1884; 2 boxes
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1837-1843; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 1)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1844; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 2)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1845; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 3)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1846-1847; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 4)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1848; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 5)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1849-1851; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 6)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1857; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 7)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1858-1859; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 8)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1860; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 9)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1861-1863; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 10)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1864; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 11)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1865; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 12)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1866; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 13)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1867; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 14)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1868; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 15)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1869; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 16)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1870; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 17)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1871; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 1)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1872; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 2)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1873-1874; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 3)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1877; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 4)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1878-1884; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 5)
        - John F. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, undated; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Frances A. Lee, 1837-1889; 1 box
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1837-1842; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 1)
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1844-1849; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 2)
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1850-1861; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 3)
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1862-1867; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 4)
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1868-1877; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 5)
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1878-1889; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 6)
        - Frances A. Lee to Samuel Phillips Lee, undated; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Family Members, 1784-1897; 2 boxes
        - Blair, Andrew Alexander - Blair, Francis Preston, 1791-1876; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 1)
        - Blair, Francis "Frank" Preston, 1821-1875; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 2)
        - Blair, James L. - Blair, Woodbury, 1843-1897; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 3)
        - Castleman, Mary M., cousin of S. Phillips Lee, 1872-1873; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 4)
        - Fitzgerald, John, grandfather of S. Phillips Lee, 1784-1893; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 5)
        - Goldsborough, Phillips Lee: AL, 1893; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 6)
        - Harrison: Henry T., Henry, Catharine, Anne, 1858-1891; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 7)
        - Lee, Alfred - Lee, Archibald H., 1848-1896; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 8)
        - Lee, Arthur - Lee, Beall, 1837-1897; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 9)
        - Lee, Blair (1857-1944): 15 ALs, 5 TLs, 1875-1895; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 10)
        - Lee, Cassius Francis - Lee, Charles Shepherd, 1844-1894; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 1)
        - Lee, Edmund Jennings - Lee, Ellen A., 1837-1895; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 2)
        - Lee, Fanny A. (1817-1889), (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson and Mrs. William Pettit, sister of S. Phillips Lee): to Elizabeth Blair Lee, 1852-1884; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 3)
          Includes 19 letters dated 1852-1884, and 33 undated letters.
        - Lee, Francis Lightfoot - Lee, Sydney Smith, 1848-1896; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 4)
        - Lee, Samuel Phillips - regarding funeral plans, 1889-1895; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 5)
        - Lee, Theodoric - Lee, William Hall, 1849-1897; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 6)
        - Pettit, Charles H.: 4 ALs, 1856-1889; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 7)
        - Pettit, William F., d. 1872, second husband of Fanny Lee Robinson: 23 ALs, 1855-1859; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 8)
        - Riggs, Boswell, nephew of S. Phillips Lee: AL, 1870; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 9)
        - Robinson, Fanny Lee (1867- ), daughter of Goldsborough Robinson: AL, 1889; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 10)
        - Robinson, Arthur Lee (1843-1888), son of Fanny Lee and Goldsborough Robinson: 4 ALs, TL, 1865-1890; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 11)
        - Robinson, Arthur Lee and Goldsborough Robinson, 1864; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 12)
        - Robinson, Goldsborough (1845-1887), son of Fanny Lee and Goldsborough Robinson: 12 ALs, 3 TLs, 1868-1886; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 13)
        - Robinson, Goldsborough (d. 1844), and R. A. Robinson: 10 ALs, 1841-1845; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 14)
        - Robinson, Phillips Lee (1874- ), son of Goldsborough Robinson: 2 ALs, 1891-1895; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 15)
        - Selden, Eliza A. (cousin of S. Phillips Lee): 5 ALs, 1872-1873; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 16)
        - Stuart: Arthur Lee, Bella, Charles Calvert, Cornelia Lee (Turberville) and S. T., 1841-1882; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 17)
        - Washington, Richard B. (nephew of Samuel Phillips Lee): AL, 1879; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 18)
        - Washington, Lawrence - Richard B. Washington, 1893-1894; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 19)
        - Yeatman, Jean Lloyd (cousin of S. Phillips Lee): 2 ALs (1892) Also AL (1805) by Francis Lightfoot Lee to his sister Sally Lee, 1805-1892; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - General, 1827-1907; 10 boxes
      Contains correspondence with tradesmen, craftsmen, farm workers, and business people, as well as invitations both professional and personal.
      - Adams - American-European Express Company, 1842-1882; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Ammen, Daniel (1820-1898): 42 ALs, 1863-1870; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Anderson - Bailey, 1840-1890; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Balch - Bell, 1848-1895; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - Belmont - Benson, 1865-1885; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1855-1859; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Biddle - Birch, 1847-1885; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Blake - Boyd, 1846-1896; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Bradfield - Bright, 1845-1879; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Brooke, John M. (1826-1906): 58 ALs, 1850-1885; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Brooke, W. I. - Case, 1838-1897; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Casey - Conroy, 1837-1897; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - Cook - Corbin, 1859-1894; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Cornwell - Cryer, 1846-1896; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Cunningham - Davenport, 1842-1897; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Davids - Dickson, 1840-1895; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Donaldson - Endicott, 1837-1887; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Etting - Fitzhugh, 1848-1890; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Flagg - Franklin, 1853-1897; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Fremont - Gales, 1863-1894; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Gantt, Thomas T. (1813- ): 72 ALs, telegram by Lee, AL by Lee, 1855-1888; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Garrett - Goldsborough, 1848-1895; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Gomez - Hanscom, 1843-1894; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Harban - Harrison, 1837-1897; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Harvey - Hitchcock, 1850-1884; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Hoar - Humphreys, 1845-1886; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Hunker - Janvier, 1835-1891; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Jarris - Jones, 1840-1884; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Kane - Kroehl, 1837-1896; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - L. R. Hamersley & Co, 1890-1897; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Lambert - Lee, 1848-1885; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - Leech, Daniel, Jr. - Lyons, N. H., 1849-1889; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - McCammon - Maury, 1839-1885; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Maxwell - Minor, 1844-1890; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - Misroon - Morton, 1837-1887; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Moses family, 1847-1880; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Moyer - National, 1848-1895; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Naval Matters - Post Retirement, 1877-1897; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 6)
        Includes information regarding a Mexican War Pension.
      - Neilson - Page, 1840-1886; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - Palmer, James C., 1837-1877 - Palmer family correspondence: 38 ALs, 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Palmer, James S. - Paulding, 1848-1878; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - Pearson - Pyne, 1839-1880; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - Quackenbush - Rives, 1827-1895; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 4)
      - Robertson - Ross, 1850-1896; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 5)
      - Rowan - Sands, 1849-1897; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - Sartori - Simmons, 1860-1890; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - Simpson - Stearns, 1838-1890; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - Steedman - Swartout, 1849-1897; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Tabor - Torbert, 1857-1878; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - Toucey - Tyler, 1844-1897; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Upham - Virginia, 1849-1895; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - Wade - Weed, 1840-1894; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - Welles, Gideon (1802-1876): 18 ALs by Welles to Lee, 7 ALs by Lee to Welles, 1862-1868; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - Welles - Winslow, 1838-1897; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Wise - Yeatman, 1845-1893; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 6)
      - Unidentified, 1886; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 7)
      - Invitations, Acceptances, Regrets, 1845-1907; 1 box (Box 95)
    - Real Estate, 1772-1912; 12 boxes
      Contains correspondence with family members involved in real estate transactions, such as Francis Preston Blair, Arthur Lee, John F. Lee, Jr., and Blair Lee, as well as agents in St. Louis, Mo., Kentucky, Maryland, and Washington, D.C., including Baggot and Haley, Isaac H. Keim, and Samuel Simmons.
      - St. Louis, 1848-1912; 8 boxes
        - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1870-1897; 4 boxes
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1870-1871; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 1)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1872; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 2)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1873; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 3)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1874; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 4)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1875; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 5)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1876; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 6)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1877; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 7)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1878; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 8)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1879; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 9)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1881; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 1)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1882; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 2)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1883; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 3)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1884; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 4)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1885; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 5)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1886; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 1)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1887; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 2)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1888 January - July; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 3)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1888 July - December; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 4)
          - Arthur Lee and John F. Lee, Jr., 1889; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 5)